<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>OpenCV on jdhao&#39;s blog</title>
    <link>https://jdhao.github.io/tags/OpenCV/</link>
    <description>Recent content in OpenCV on jdhao&#39;s blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>jdhao</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 17 Mar 2020 23:08:32 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://jdhao.github.io/tags/OpenCV/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Conversion between base64 and OpenCV or PIL Image</title>
      <link>https://jdhao.github.io/2020/03/17/base64_opencv_pil_image_conversion/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Mar 2020 23:08:32 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jdhao.github.io/2020/03/17/base64_opencv_pil_image_conversion/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When we are building web services using Python, we often send or receive images
in &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.python.org/3/library/base64.html&#34;&gt;base64&lt;/a&gt; encoded format.
However, when we are doing image processing tasks, we need to use PIL or
OpenCV. In this post, I will share how to convert between OpenCV or PIL image
and base64 encoded image.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Read and Write Images with Unicode Paths in OpenCV</title>
      <link>https://jdhao.github.io/2019/09/11/opencv_unicode_image_path/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2019 00:23:41 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jdhao.github.io/2019/09/11/opencv_unicode_image_path/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The other day, when I was using OpenCV to read some images and print the image
shape, I got an error:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;lsquo;NoneType&amp;rsquo; object has no attribute &amp;lsquo;shape&amp;rsquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was confused and do not know why since the image path is valid. It tooks me a
while to understand the cause.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Convert PIL or OpenCV Image to Bytes without Saving to Disk</title>
      <link>https://jdhao.github.io/2019/07/06/python_opencv_pil_image_to_bytes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Jul 2019 22:18:22 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jdhao.github.io/2019/07/06/python_opencv_pil_image_to_bytes/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sometimes, we may want an in-memory jpg or png image that is represented as
binary data. But often, what we have got is image in OpenCV (Numpy ndarray) or
PIL Image format. In this post, I will share how to convert Numpy image or PIL
Image object to binary data without saving the underlying image to disk.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cropping Rotated Rectangles from Image with OpenCV</title>
      <link>https://jdhao.github.io/2019/02/23/crop_rotated_rectangle_opencv/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Feb 2019 01:14:26 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jdhao.github.io/2019/02/23/crop_rotated_rectangle_opencv/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In computer vision tasks, we need to crop a rotated rectangle from the original
image sometimes, for example, to crop a rotated text box. In this post, I would
like to introduce how to do this in OpenCV.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Resize, Pad Image to Square Shape and Keep Its Aspect Ratio in Python</title>
      <link>https://jdhao.github.io/2017/11/06/resize-image-to-square-with-padding/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Nov 2017 10:00:45 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jdhao.github.io/2017/11/06/resize-image-to-square-with-padding/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When we are using convolutional neural networks, most of the time, we need to
fix the input image size to feed it to the network. The usual practice is to
resize the input image to the given size (the image aspect ratio is no longer
kept) and then crop a fixed size patch randomly from the resized image. This
practice may work well for image classification where fine details may not be
necessary. But for Image retrieval, we want to keep the image aspect ration
unchanged. In this post, I will summarize ways to resize an image to square
shape with padding and keep its aspect ratio.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>